How hot is it? Hot enough to cook an egg
on the street.
>> This is 1010 Winds. You give us 22
minutes, we'll give you the world.
>> The heat dome is indeed upon us
>> with the dangerously high temperatures.
>> Dangerous heat levels.
>> Hottest temperatures really in 14 years.
This is dangerous heat.
How hot does a surface need to be to
cook an egg on it?
>> Around 150 to 160° F.
>> This isn't just a street. There are
these metal plates on the street and
there's steam coming up. So, this might
be the hottest street in all of New York
City.
Sorry, making lunch.
Behind me here is the Brooklyn Bridge
City Hall subway station. Now, according
to Google, this is one of the hottest
subway stations in the city. Outside,
it's currently about 105°.
None of the subway stations are airond
conditioned cuz they're all open. You
just like walk in.
>> It is swampy down here.
>> Not bad.
What's amazing is the disparity between
the subway platform
and being on the train. 34° difference
between the platform and on the train.
library, one of New York City's
designated cooling centers. So, if if
you're really hot and you need some
place to go, you go in there and then
it's outside the library. It's about
112°.
>> That's not allowed in the building. Is
that a motorized thing there?
>> Yeah, it has a motor on it.
>> No, it's not allowed in the building.
>> I can't bring this in.
>> No.
>> All right, let me just check the
temperature.
>> Bags open, everyone.
>> 71°
in here. I said to that guy, stay cool.
and he said, "I'm always cool."
Time Square temp check. 106.5°.
This is a cooling tent.
Some
101°.
This is Central Park's sheep meadow. And
the sheep meadow is usually like where
you come on a hot summer day in New York
City to like hang out, throw a frisbee.
What's surprising is that it's empty.
The whole city's empty. Everywhere I've
skate around is just empty. This might
be one of the quietest days I've ever
seen in New York. Obviously, cuz I guess
people are just staying inside today.
How many miles are you running today?
>> Uh 15 hopefully.
>> 15?
>> Yes.
>> Why would you pick today of all days to
run 15 miles?
>> We have to get the mileage in
eventually.
>> Lionus, good luck with the long run.
>> Found a couple people. They're swimming
in the fountain in Washington Square
Park.
Yeah.
All right. This massive traffic jam
right here, these are all people waiting
to get on the Holland Tunnel. This is
everyone trying to leave New York City
right now. And it's just jammed as far
as the eye can see.
I got to install this. You see,
yesterday my air conditioner exploded.
My air conditioner's on fire.
Oh god,
should have cleaned that.
Worst heat wave in a decade in my air.
I wish you could smell what it smells
like in here.
>> You need
to find the air conditioners.
Keep
coming.
49°.
Excellent.
He's got to be hot up there.
>> How do you handle the heat on a day like
today?
>> You look hot right now. How do I handle
the heat? I try to I try to I try to um
Tons of water. Tons of water. My
partner, he always holding me down.
>> Like, share, subscribe. The best dude
ever.
>> I appreciate you.
>> Yeah. Appreciate it.
>> Take care. Stay cool, guys. Stay cool.
>> Do you know where those like the
sprinkler caps for the hydrants? Do you
know if any are set up around here?
>> Typically, we get requested.
>> So, if someone wants one, you like teach
them how or whatever. No, we we cuz some
of them only we could turn on.
>> Oh,
>> so it's a bit of a like a New York City
tradition to open up fire hydrants and
then the kids like play in the street in
the fire hydrant water. But if you just
open up a fire hydrant and let it flow,
it'll release 1,000 gallons of water
every minute. So they put these special
sprinkler caps on them and it's only
like 20 gallons a minute and kids can
play in it and stuff. And the city kind
of sanctions it. You just go to a
firehouse and they like set it up for
you.
>> Did you guys set this up or the fire
department did it?
>> You guys did this.
I'm trying to do something
about 100 106°
right here. Okay, here's my hot take on
New York City in the summer. If you're a
tourist and you want to come visit this
city, come in the peak of the summer. No
one is here. The city is completely
yours. You get restaurants,
reservations, there's like you won't get
pushed off the sidewalk. Come in the
summer because every New Yorker leaves.
I'm leaving. I'm leaving right now.
How you doing? It's good
to JFK.
Thank you very much, sir. Have a good
day.
>> Continue with the boarding process and
time.